Auricia V Guardado

E: auricia.guardado@gmail.com · M: (402) 378-2765 · Olympia, Washington 98501

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/auricia-v-guardado-599883a0 Github: https://github.com/guaaur04 Website: https://guaaur04.github.io/updated_portfolio/

Cooperative Business Studies graduate with sights set on a full-time web development position. Experienced in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, Node Js,

MySQL, Sequelize . Passionate about collaboration, creativity, and language learning with

fluency in Spanish/English, and a student of Portuguese,.

Technical Skills

Node.Js, Javascript, JQuery, Github, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, AJAX, MySQL, MySQL2, Sequelize, Heroku deployment, the command line, computer science fundamentals, robotics engineering fundamentals.

Applications

Study Kanji

Designed for those looking to learn Japanese in a simple and user friendly way. Understanding the Kanji is a very basic stepping stone as an introduction to the language.

Live Site - https://desasser.github.io/Japanese-Study-App/
GitHub Repo - https://github.com/desasser/Japanese-Study-App/

Password Generator

The Random Password Generator creates passwords between 8-128 characters.

Live Site - https://desasser.github.io/Japanese-Study-App/

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/desasser/Japanese-Study-App

Weather Dashboard

Incorporates Weather API- current weather, 5-day forecast, UV Index, and icon database.

Github: https://github.com/guaaur04/api-weather-dashboard/ Live Site: https://guaaur04.github.io/api-weather-dashboard/

Restaurant Administrative Dashboard

Built for Pizza Cutter, Michigan since 1975. This application allows restaurant managers the ability to easily edit the content of their website.

Live Site - https://pizzacutterapp.herokuapp.com/pizzacutter GitHub Repo - https://github.com/zhuxiaoyu1019/online-order-system

Education

University of Washington · Seattle, Washington · Graduation: 2021 · Certificate in Full-Flex Stack Development

The Evergreen State College · Olympia, Washington · Graduation: 2016 · Bachelor of Arts (B.A) with concentrations in Cooperative Business Management, Latin American Studies, and Political Economy.

Maywood Academy High School · Maywood, California · Graduation: June 2011

East Los Angeles College · East Los Angeles, California · 2010 · Junior Engineering & Technology Academy

Relevant Coursework

Independent Learning Contract: Visions of Change: Community Organizing through Cooperative/Collective Models · The Evergreen State College · 2015

Internship Learning Contract: Cooperative Finances at The Flaming Eggplant Café · The Evergreen State College · 2016

Thurston Santo Tomás Sister County Association Exchange Delegation · The Evergreen State College · Santo Tomas, Chontales, Nicaragua · 2015

Achievements

Rosa Parks Social Justice Award · 2011

Publications

Writing American Cultures • The Evergreen State College Press • 2013

Skills

Bilingual: Spanish/English · Point of Sales System Management · Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite: advanced Excel · Word · PowerPoint · Access · Can type

Work Experience

New Moon Cooperative Cafe · Olympia, Washington · September 2016-Current Worker-Owner

THE FLAMING EGGPLANT COOPERATIVE/COLLECTIVE CAFÉ \cdot Olympia, Washington \cdot

September 2013-June 2016

Vendor Relations, September 2013-June 2014

- Maintain friendly relationships with vendors
- Analyze food costs and inventory
- Maintain a fully stocked café

Cashier and Barista, September 2013-June 2016

- Completed front of house responsibilities such as opening/closing procedures, cash register operations, maintained a clean workspace, and familiarity with health code Espresso beverage preparation
- Provided excellent customer service
- Trained workers on cashier/barista shift work on multiple occasions, including POS operations and espresso preparation

Financial Liaison, June 2014-June 2016

- Maintained responsibility for the management, oversight and strategic planning of the café's financial activity
- Planned and implemented long- and short- range financial goals for the café including the annual analysis and reporting of sales, product pricing, and budget expenditures Reported financial standing to collective and board of advisors
- Analyzed customized reports and internal deposit data to make recommendations Facilitated the participation of the collective in budget decisions
- Prepared annual budgets
- Communicated advantages of financial responsibility to café
- Engaged data entry for the café's Expense Ledger

TRiO Program· Olympia, Washington · Fall 2012-Spring 2013 Peer Leader

- Developed/presented workshops, and provided academic support/mentoring for 1st/2nd year college students at the Evergreen State College
- Created promotional material
- Held office hours

References

Lizzy Rieke
The Flaming Eggplant Café Advisor
Olympia, Washington
(360) 867 6092
riekee@evergreen.edu

Gregory Porter Student Activities Productions Advisor Olympia, Washington (360) 867-6222 porterg@evergreen.edu

Jean Eberhardt

Academic Advisor at the Evergreen State College eberhardtjl@yahoo.com (360) 943-8642